You know, I didn't set out to be a parenting expert.
لم أخطط لأكون خبيرة في تربية الأبناء.
In fact, I'm not very interested in parenting, per Se.
في الواقع، أنا لست مهتمة كثيرًا بتربية الأبناء، في حد ذاتها.
It's just that there's a certain style of parenting these days
هناك فقط نمط تربية معين في هذه الأيام
that is kind of messing up kids,
يفسد الأبناء نوعًا ما،
impeding their chances to develop into theirselves.
ويعوق فرصهم في التطور ليصبحوا أنفسهم.
There's a certain style of parenting these days
هناك نمط تربية معين في هذه الأيام
that's getting in the way.
يُعرقل الطريق.
I guess what I'm saying is,
ما أريدُ قوله هو،
we spend a lot of time being very concerned
أننا ننفق الكثير من الوقت في القلق كثيرًا
about parents who aren't involved enough in the lives of their kids
حول الآباء والأمهات الذين لا يشاركون بما فيه الكفاية في حياة أبنائهم
and their education or their upbringing,
وتعليمهم أو تربيتهم،
and rightly so.
ونحن محقون في ذلك.
But at the other end of the spectrum,
ولكن علي الجانب الأخر من الأمر،
there's a lot of harm going on there as well,
هناك أذى كثير يحصل أيضًا،
where parents feel a kid can't be successful
حين يشعر الأهل أن الطفل لا يمكن أن ينجح
unless the parent is protecting and preventing at every turn
إلا تحت الحماية والتدخل المستمرين للأب أو الأم
and hovering over every happening, and micromanaging every moment,
والتخطيط المسبق لأي حدث ، وتسيير كل لحظة ،
and steering their kid towards some small subset of colleges and careers.
وتوجيه الطفل نحو نوعية صغيرة من الجامعات والمهن.
When we raise kids this way,
عندما نربي الأطفال بهذه الطريقة،
and I'll say we,
وأنا أقول "نحن"،
because Lord knows, in raising my two teenagers,
لأن الرب يعلم، أنني وخلال تربيتي لولداي المراهقين،
I've had these tendencies myself,
كانت لدي أنا أيضًا هذه الميول،
our kids end up leading a kind of checklisted childhood.
ينتهي الأمر بعيش أبنائنا طفولة مرسومة ومحددة.
And here's what the checklisted childhood looks like.
وهذا هو ما تبدو عليه هذه الطفولة.
We keep them safe and sound
نحن نحافظ على سلامتهم وأمنهم،
and fed and watered,
ونوفر لهم المأكل والمشرب،
and then we want to be sure they go to the right schools,
وبعدها نريد أن نتأكد أنهم سيذهبون إلى المدارس المناسبة،
that they're in the right classes at the right schools,
والصفوف المناسبة في المدارس المناسبة،
And check the box for community service.
وضعوا علامة في خانة خدمة المجتمع.
I mean, show the colleges you care about others.
وأظهروا للجامعات أنكم تهتمون بالآخرين.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And all of this is done to some hoped-for degree of perfection.
ويتم كل هذا في أمل الوصول إلى درجة من الكمال.
We expect our kids to perform at a level of perfection
نحن نتوقع من أبنائنا أن يقدموا أداء على مستوى معين من الكمال
we were never asked to perform at ourselves,
لم نستطع نحن أنفسنا الوصول إليه،
and so because so much is required,
ولأن المطالب كثيرة،
we think,
فنحن نعتقد،
well then, of course we parents have to argue with every teacher
أنه يجب علينا طبعًا كآباء مجادلة كل مدرس
and principal and coach and referee
ومدير ومدرب وحَكَم
and act like our kid's concierge
ونتصرف مثل بَوَّابً لطفلنا
and personal handler
وراعٍ شخصي
and secretary.
وسكرتير.
And then with our kids, our precious kids,
وأيضًا مع أطفالنا، أطفالنا الغالين،
we spend so much time nudging,
نقضي الكثير من الوقت في تشجيعهم،
cajoling, hinting, helping, haggling, nagging as the case may be,
والتملق وتقديم المشورة والمساعدة لهم ومساومتهم ومضايقتهم إذا تطلب الأمر،
to be sure they're not screwing up,
للتأكد من أنهم لن يفسدوا الأمر،
not closing doors,
لن يغلقوا الأبواب،
not ruining their future,
ولن يدمروا مستقبلهم،
some hoped-for admission
وقبول مأمول
to a tiny handful of colleges
للذهاب لنوع معين من الجامعات
that deny almost every applicant.
التي ترفض كل المرشحين تقريبًا.
And here's what it feels like to be a kid in this checklisted childhood.
وهذا هو ما يشعر به أي طفل يعيش هذه الطفولة المرسومة.
First of all, there's no time for free play.
أولاً وقبل كل شيء، ليس هناك وقت للعب .
There's no room in the afternoons,
ليس هناك فراغ في فترة بعد الظهر،
because everything has to be enriching, we think.
لأننا نعتقد أن كل شيء يجب أن يكون مثريًا.
It's as if every piece of homework, every quiz, every activity
كما لو أن كل واجب منزلي، كل مسابقة، كل نشاط
is a make-or-break moment for this future we have in mind for them,
هي لحظة قرار حاسمة بالنسبة لهذا المستقبل الذي نتصوره لهم،
and we absolve them of helping out around the house,
ونحن نعفيهم من المساعدة في الأعمال المنزلية،
and we even absolve them of getting enough sleep
ونعفيهم حتى من الحصول على القدر الكافي من النوم
as long as they're checking off the items on their checklist.
طالما هم في طور إنجاز الأمور المدرجة على قائمتهم.
And in the checklisted childhood, we say we just want them to be happy,
وخلال هذه الطفولة المرسومة، نقول أننا نريد فقط أن يكونوا سعداء،
but when they come home from school,
ولكن عندما يأتون من المدرسة إلى البيت،
what we ask about all too often first
فإن أول ما نسأل عنه غالبًا
is their homework and their grades.
هو واجباتهم ودرجاتهم.
And they see in our faces
وهم يرون على وجوهنا
that our approval, that our love,
أن موافقتنا، أن حبنا،
that their very worth,
أن قيمتهم بحد ذاتها،
comes from A's.
مقرونة بتحصيلهم درجة "ممتاز".
And then we walk alongside them
ثم نسير بجانبهم
and offer clucking praise like a trainer at the Westminster Dog Show --
ونقَرْقِر كالدجاج بالثناء مثل مدرب في برنامج استعراضي للكلاب -
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
coaxing them to just jump a little higher and soar a little farther,
محاولين إقناعهم بالقفز إلى الأعلى قليلاً والتحليق أبعد قليلاً،
day after day after day.
يومًا بعد يوم بعد يوم.
And when they get to high school,
وعندما يصلون إلى المرحلة الثانوية،
they don't say, "Well, what might I be interested in studying
لا يتساءلون: "حسنًا، ما هو المجال الذي أرغب في دراسته؟
or doing as an activity?"
أو النشاط الذي أريد ممارسته؟"
They go to counselors and they say,
إنهم يذهبون إلى المستشارين ويقولون:
"What do I need to do to get into the right college?"
"ما الذي يجب علي القيام به للذهاب للجامعة المناسبة؟"
And then, when the grades start to roll in in high school,
وبعد ذلك، عندما تبدأ الدرجات بالانخفاض في المدرسة الثانوية،
and they're getting some B's,
ويحصلون على درجة "جيد جدًا"،
or God forbid some C's,
أو درجة "جيد" لا سمح الله،
they frantically text their friends
فإنهم يراسلون أصدقائهم ويسألون:
and say, "Has anyone ever gotten into the right college with these grades?"
" هل استطاع شخص ما من قبل الذهاب للجامعة المناسبة بدرجات كهذه؟"
And our kids,
وأطفالنا،
regardless of where they end up at the end of high school,
بغض النظر عن المكان الذي يذهبون إليه بعد المرحلة الثانوية،
they're breathless.
يكونون قد استهلكوا أنْفَاسهم بالكامل.
They're brittle.
يصابون بالهشاشة
They're a little burned out.
والإرهاق.
They're a little old before their time,
ويكبرون قبل الأوان،
wishing the grown-ups in their lives had said, "What you've done is enough,
متمنين أن الأشخاص البالغين في حياتهم قالوا: "ما قمتَ به كاف،
this effort you've put forth in childhood is enough."
الجهد الذي بذلتَه خلال طفولتك كاف."
And they're withering now under high rates of anxiety and depression
وهم يُدمَّرون الآن بمعدلات عالية من القلق والاكتئاب
and some of them are wondering,
وبعضهم يتساءلون
will this life ever turn out to have been worth it?
ما إذا كانت هذه الحياة تستحق كل هذا العناء.
Well, we parents,
نحن، الآباء،
we parents are pretty sure it's all worth it.
نحن الآباء واثقون تمامًا أن الأمر يستحق كل هذا العناء.
We seem to behave --
إننا نتصرف -
it's like we literally think they will have no future
كما لو أننا نعتقد حرفيًا أنه لا مستقبل لهم
if they don't get into one of these tiny set of colleges or careers
إذا لم يذهبوا لإحدى تلك الجامعات أو المهن
we have in mind for them.
التي نريدها لهم.
Or maybe, maybe, we're just afraid
أو ربما، ربما، نحن نخشى فقط
they won't have a future we can brag about
من عدم حصولهم على مستقبل يمكننا التباهي به
to our friends and with stickers on the backs of our cars.
أمام أصدقائنا وفي ملصقات على سياراتنا.
Yeah.
بلى.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But if you look at what we've done,
ولكن إذا نظرتم إلى ما فعلناه،
if you have the courage to really look at it,
إذا كانت لديكم الشجاعة فعلاً للنظر في ذلك،
you'll see that not only do our kids think their worth comes
فسترون أن أبناءنا لا يعتقدون فقط أن قيمتهم مقرونة
from grades and scores,
بالدرجات والعلامات،
but that when we live right up inside their precious developing minds
ولكننا عندما نعيش فعليًا داخل عقولهم الغالية الموجودة قيد التطوير
all the time, like our very own version of the movie "Being John Malkovich,"
طوال الوقت، مثل نسختنا الخاصة من فيلم "أن تكون جون مالكوفيتش "
we send our children the message:
نحن نرسل لأبنائنا هذه الرسالة:
"Hey kid, I don't think you can actually achieve any of this without me."
"يا ولد، أنا لا أعتقد أنه يمكنك فعلاً تحقيق أي من هذا بدوني".
And so with our overhelp,
ومن خلال مساعدتنا المبالغ فيها
our overprotection and overdirection and hand-holding,
وحمايتنا الزائدة وتوجيهنا الزائد وأخذنا بأيديهم،
we deprive our kids of the chance to build self-efficacy,
فنحن نحرم أطفالنا من فرصة بناء الكفاءة الذاتية،
which is a really fundamental tenet of the human psyche,
التي هي مبدأ أساسي من النفس البشرية،
far more important than that self-esteem they get
أهم بكثير من احترام الذات الذي يكسبونه
every time we applaud.
كلما امتدحناهم.
Self-efficacy is built when one sees that one's own actions lead to outcomes,
إن الكفاءة الذاتية تُبنى عندما يرى المرء أن أفعاله تؤدي إلى نتائج،
not --
ليس -
There you go.
هكذا بالضبط.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Not one's parents' actions on one's behalf,
ليس تصرفات والدي المرء نيابة عنه،
but when one's own actions lead to outcomes.
ولكن عندما تؤدي تصرفات المرء بنفسه إلى نتائج.
So simply put,
إذن وببساطة،
if our children are to develop self-efficacy, and they must,
لكي يكتسب أطفالنا الكفاءة الذاتية، ويجب عليهم ذلك،
then they have to do a whole lot more of the thinking, planning, deciding,
فإنه يتعين عليهم القيام بالكثير من التفكير والتخطيط واتخاذ القرار
doing, hoping, coping, trial and error,
والعمل والأمل والمواجهة والتجربة والخطأ،
dreaming and experiencing of life
والحلم واختبار الحياة
for themselves.
بأنفسهم.
Now, am I saying
الآن، هل يعني هذا
every kid is hard-working and motivated
أن كل الأطفال يعملون بجد ومتحمسون
and doesn't need a parent's involvement or interest in their lives,
ولا يحتاج أي منهم إلى تدخل الوالدين أو اهتمامهم في حياتهم،
and we should just back off and let go?
وأن علينا أن ننسحب وندعهم لحالهم؟ .
Hell no.
قطعًا لا!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That is not what I'm saying.
ليس هذا ما أقوله.
What I'm saying is, when we treat grades and scores and accolades and awards
ما أقوله هو، أننا عندما نتعامل مع الرتب والدرجات والأوسمة والجوائز
as the purpose of childhood,
باعتبارها الهدف من الطفولة،
all in furtherance of some hoped-for admission to a tiny number of colleges
في سبيل تعزيز قبول مأمول للذهاب لنوعية صغيرة جدًا من الجامعات
or entrance to a small number of careers,
أو الحصول علي عدد قليل من الوظائف،
that that's too narrow a definition of success for our kids.
وهذا تضييق لمفهوم النجاح بالنسبة لأطفالنا.
And even though we might help them achieve some short-term wins
وعلى الرغم من أننا قد نساعدهم على تحقيق بعض المكاسب القصيرة الأمد
by overhelping --
عبر المساعدة المبالغ فيها-
like they get a better grade if we help them do their homework,
مثل حصوهم على درجة أفضل إذا ساعدناهم في أداء الواجبات،
they might end up with a longer childhood résumé when we help --
وحصولهم على سيرة ذاتية أطول لطفولتهم عندما نساعدهم -
what I'm saying is that all of this comes at a long-term cost
ما أقوله هو أن كل هذا يأتي مقابل تكلفة طويلة الأمد
to their sense of self.
لتصورهم عن أنفسهم.
What I'm saying is, we should be less concerned
يجب علينا أن نكون أقل قلقًا
with the specific set of colleges
حول المجموعة المحددة من الجامعات
they might be able to apply to or might get into
التي يمكن لهم التقدم إليها
and far more concerned that they have the habits, the mindset, the skill set,
وأكثر قلقًا حول ما إذا كانوا يمتلكون العادات وطريقة التفكير والمهارات،
the wellness, to be successful wherever they go.
والعافية، ليكونوا ناجحين أينما ذهبوا.
What I'm saying is,
ما أقوله هو،
our kids need us to be a little less obsessed with grades and scores
أطفالنا بحاجة إلى أن نكون نحن أقل هوسًا بالرتب والدرجات
and a whole lot more interested
وأكثر اهتمامًا
in childhood providing a foundation for their success
بتوفير طفولة تكون أساسًا لنجاحهم
built on things like love
ومبنية على أمور مثل الحب
and chores.
والأشغال المنزلية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Did I just say chores? Did I just say chores? I really did.
هل قلت للتو أشغالاً منزلية؟ هل قلت ذلك؟ نعم.
But really, here's why.
ولكن إليكم السبب.
The longest longitudinal study of humans ever conducted
أطول دراسة مستمرة أجريت على البشر
is called the Harvard Grant Study.
تسمى دراسة "هارفارد جرانت".
It found that professional success in life,
وجدت أن النجاح المهني في الحياة،
which is what we want for our kids,
وهو ما نريده لأبنائنا،
that professional success in life comes from having done chores as a kid,
أن النجاح المهني في الحياة مرتبط بإنجاز الأشغال المنزلية خلال الطفولة،
and the earlier you started, the better,
وكلما كان ذلك مبكرًا، كان أفضل،
that a roll-up-your-sleeves- and-pitch-in mindset,
أن عقلية المبادرة والمشاركة ،
a mindset that says, there's some unpleasant work,
والتفكير الذي يقول: هناك بعض الأعمال غير السارة،
someone's got to do it, it might as well be me,
يجب على شخص ما إنجازها، لم لا أكون أنا ذلك الشخص؟
a mindset that says,
التفكير الذي يقول:
I will contribute my effort to the betterment of the whole,
سأقدم جهودي في سبيل المنفعة العامة،
that that's what gets you ahead in the workplace.
هذا هو ما يجعلك متفوقًًا في مكان العمل.
Now, we all know this. You know this.
الآن، نحن جميعًا نعرف هذا. أنتم تعرفون هذا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
We all know this, and yet, in the checklisted childhood,
نحن نعرف هذا جميعًا، ولكن خلال تلك الطفولة المرسومة،
we absolve our kids of doing the work of chores around the house,
نحن نعفي أطفالنا من القيام بالأشغال المنزلية،
and then they end up as young adults in the workplace
وعندما يصلون مرحلة العمل كشباب
still waiting for a checklist,
لايزالون في انتظار قائمة مهام،
but it doesn't exist,
ولكنها غير موجودة
and more importantly, lacking the impulse, the instinct
والأهم من ذلك، يفتقرون إلى الدافع والغريزة
to roll up their sleeves and pitch in
للمبادرة والمشاركة
and look around and wonder, how can I be useful to my colleagues?
والنظر حولهم والتساؤل: كيف يمكنني مساعدة زملائي؟
How can I anticipate a few steps ahead to what my boss might need?
كيف يمكنني توقع ما قد يحتاجه مديري مسبقًا؟
A second very important finding from the Harvard Grant Study
وثاني اكتشاف مهم جدًا لدراسة "هارفارد جرانت"
said that happiness in life
يقول أن السعادة في الحياة
comes from love,
تأتي من الحب،
not love of work,
ليس حب العمل،
love of humans:
بل حب الأشخاص:
our spouse, our partner, our friends, our family.
أزواجنا وشركاؤنا وأصدقاؤنا وعائلتنا.
So childhood needs to teach our kids how to love,
لذا فالطفولة يجب أن تعلم أطفالنا كيف يحبون،
and they can't love others if they don't first love themselves,
ولا يمكنهم أن يحبوا الآخرين إذا لم يحبوا أنفسهم أولاً،
and they won't love themselves if we can't offer them unconditional love.
ولن يحبوا أنفسهم إذا لم نستطع أن نقدم لهم حُبًا غير مشروط.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Right.
تمامًا.
And so,
وهكذا،
instead of being obsessed with grades and scores
بدلاً من أن نكون مهووسين بالرتب والدرجات
when our precious offspring come home from school,
عندما يأتي أبناؤنا الغاليين من المدرسة إلى البيت،
or we come home from work,
أو نأتي نحن من العمل،
we need to close our technology, put away our phones,
فنحن بحاجة للإبتعاد عن التكنولوجيا، وترك هواتفنا
and look them in the eye
وأن ننظر إلى أعينهم
and let them see the joy that fills our faces
وندعهم يرون الفرح الذي يملأ وجوهنا
when we see our child for the first time in a few hours.
عندما نرى طفلنا لأول مرة بعد بضع ساعات.
And then we have to say,
ومن ثم يجب علينا أن نسألهم:
"How was your day?
"كيف كان يومك؟
What did you like about today?"
ما الذي أعجبك اليوم؟"
And when your teenage daughter says, "Lunch," like mine did,
وعندما ترد ابنتك المراهقة ب "الغداء"، مثلما فعلت ابنتي،
and I want to hear about the math test,
وأنا أريد أن أعرف نتيجة اختبار الرياضيات،
not lunch,
لا الغداء،
you have to still take an interest in lunch.
فيجب عليك إظهار اهتمام بالغذاء.
You gotta say, "What was great about lunch today?"
وتقول: "ما الرائع في غداء اليوم؟"
They need to know they matter to us as humans,
هم بحاجة إلى معرفة أنهم مهمّون بالنسبة لنا باعتبارهم بَشرًا،
not because of their GPA.
وليس بسبب معدلاتهم.
All right, so you're thinking, chores and love,
حسنًا، أنتم تفكرون : أشغال منزلية وحب،
that sounds all well and good, but give me a break.
هذا يبدو جيدًا، ولكن فلنكن واقعيين.
The colleges want to see top scores and grades
الجامعات تريد رؤية نتائج ودرجات عالية
and accolades and awards, and I'm going to tell you, sort of.
وتقديرات وجوائز، وهذا صحيح نوعًا ما.
The very biggest brand-name schools are asking that of our young adults,
المدارس الكبرى تطلب ذلك من شبابنا،
but here's the good news.
ولكن ها هي الأخبار الجيدة.
Contrary to what the college rankings racket would have us believe --
على عكس ما تُروج له تصنيفات الجامعات -
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
you don't have to go to one of the biggest brand name schools
فإنه لا يجب عليك الذهاب إلى إحدى المدارس الكبرى
to be happy and successful in life.
لكي تكون سعيدًا وناجحًا في الحياة.
Happy and successful people went to state school,
فالأشخاص السعداء والناجحين ذهبوا لمدارس حكومية،
went to a small college no one has heard of,
وكليات صغيرة غير معروفة،
went to community college,
ذهبوا إلى كليات المجتمع،
went to a college over here and flunked out.
ذهبوا إلى جامعة ما وفشلوا بها.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
The evidence is in this room, is in our communities,
والدليل على ذلك موجود في هذه الغرفة، في مجتمعاتنا،
that this is the truth.
على أن هذه هي الحقيقة.
And if we could widen our blinders
وإذا ما تمكنا من توسيع رؤيتنا
and be willing to look at a few more colleges,
وصرنا مستعدين لأخذ جامعات أخرى بعين الاعتبار،
maybe remove our own egos from the equation,
وتخلينا عن الأنا الخاصة بنا من المعادلة،
we could accept and embrace this truth and then realize,
فيمكننا أن نقبل ونتقبل هذه الحقيقة ثم ندرك،
it is hardly the end of the world
أن هذه ليست نهاية العالم
if our kids don't go to one of those big brand-name schools.
إذا لم يذهب أبناؤنا لإحدى تلك المدارس الكبرى.
And more importantly,
والأهم من ذلك،
if their childhood has not been lived according to a tyrannical checklist
إذا لم يعيشوا طفولتهم وفقًا لقائمة مهام مستبدة
then when they get to college,
فعندما يذهبون إلى الجامعة،
whichever one it is,
كيفما كانت،
well, they'll have gone there on their own volition,
فسيذهبون إليها بمحض إرادتهم،
fueled by their own desire,
مدعَّمين برغبتهم،
capable and ready to thrive there.
مؤهلين وجاهزين للازدهار هناك.
I have to admit something to you.
يجب علي أن أعترف لكم بأمر ما.
I've got two kids I mentioned, Sawyer and Avery.
أنا عندي اثنين من الأبناء كما ذكرت، سوير وأفيري.
They're teenagers.
هما مراهقان.
And once upon a time,
وفي وقت ما،
I think I was treating my Sawyer and Avery
أعتقد أنني كنت أعاملهما نوعًا ما
like little bonsai trees --
كأشجار بونساي -
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
that I was going to carefully clip and prune
كنت أنوي تقطيعها وتقليمها بعناية
and shape into some perfect form of a human
وتشكيلها إلى إنسان مثالي
that might just be perfect enough to warrant them admission
مثاليًا بما يكفي لدخول
to one of the most highly selective colleges.
إحدى الجامعات الأكثر انتقائية.
But I've come to realize, after working with thousands of other people's kids --
ولكني أدركت، بعدما عملت مع الآلاف من الأطفال -
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and raising two kids of my own,
وتربية ابني وابنتي،
my kids aren't bonsai trees.
أن أطفالي ليسوا أشجار بونساي.
They're wildflowers
بل أزهار برية
of an unknown genus and species --
من جنس ونوع مجهولين -
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and it's my job to provide a nourishing environment,
ووظيفتي هي توفير بيئة مغذية،
to strengthen them through chores
لتقويتهما من خلال الأشغال المنزلية
and to love them so they can love others and receive love
وأحبهما حتى يُحبا الآخرين ويتلقيا الحب
and the college, the major, the career,
والجامعة والتخصص والمهنة،
that's up to them.
ذلك متروك لهم.
My job is not to make them become what I would have them become,
وظيفتي ليست جعلهم كما أريد،
but to support them in becoming their glorious selves.
بل تقديم الدعم لهم حتى يصبحوا رائعين في أنفسهم.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)